So isn't it amazing how much control the attackers can get with such a simple operation? Let me show you how most malware is now distributed today. What I'm going to do is open up a website that I wrote. It's a terrible website. It's got really awful graphics. And it's got a comments section here where we can submit comments to the website. Many of you will have used something a bit like this before. Unfortunately, when this was implemented, the developer was slightly inebriated and managed to forget all of the secure coding practices he had learned. So let's imagine that our attacker, called Evil Hacker just for comedy value, inserts something a little nasty. This is a script. It's code which will be interpreted on the webpage. So I'm going to submit this post, and then, on my victim computer, I'm going to open up the web browser and browse to my website, www.incrediblyhacked.com. Notice that after a couple of seconds, I get redirected. That website address at the top there, which you can just about see, microshaft.com, the browser crashes as it hits one of these exploit packs, and up pops fake antivirus. This is a virus pretending to look like antivirus software, and it will go through and it will scan the system, have a look at what its popping up here. It creates some very serious alerts. Oh look, a child porn proxy server. We really should clean that up. What's really insulting about this is not only does it provide the attackers with access to your data, but when the scan finishes, they tell you in order to clean up the fake viruses, you have to register the product. Now I liked it better when viruses were free. (Laughter) People now pay cybercriminals money to run viruses, which I find utterly bizarre. So anyway, let me change pace a little bit. Chasing 250,000 pieces of malware a day is a massive challenge, and those numbers are only growing directly in proportion to the length of my stress line, you'll note here. So I want to talk to you briefly about a group of hackers we tracked for a year and actually found -- and this is a rare treat in our job. Now this was a cross-industry collaboration, people from Facebook, independent researchers, guys from Sophos. So here we have a couple of documents which our cybercriminals had uploaded to a cloud service, kind of like Dropbox or SkyDrive, like many of you might use. At the top, you'll notice a section of source code. What this would do is send the cybercriminals a text message every day telling them how much money they'd made that day, so a kind of cybercriminal billings report, if you will. If you look closely, you'll notice a series of what are Russian telephone numbers. Now that's obviously interesting, because that gives us a way of finding our cybercriminals. Down below, highlighted in red, in the other section of source code, is this bit "leded:leded." That's a username, kind of like you might have on Twitter. So let's take this a little further. There are a few other interesting pieces the cybercriminals had uploaded. Lots of you here will use smartphones to take photos and post them from the conference. An interesting feature of lots of modern smartphones is that when you take a photo, it embeds GPS data about where that photo was taken. In fact, I've been spending a lot of time on Internet dating sites recently, obviously for research purposes, and I've noticed that about 60 percent of the profile pictures on Internet dating sites contain the GPS coordinates of where the photo was taken, which is kind of scary because you wouldn't give out your home address to lots of strangers, but we're happy to give away our GPS coordinates to plus or minus 15 meters. And our cybercriminals had done the same thing. So here's a photo which resolves to St. Petersburg. We then deploy the incredibly advanced hacking tool. We used Google. Using the email address, the telephone number and the GPS data, on the left you see an advert for a BMW that one of our cybercriminals is selling, on the other side an advert for the sale of sphynx kittens. One of these was more stereotypical for me. A little more searching, and here's our cybercriminal. Imagine, these are hardened cybercriminals sharing information scarcely. Imagine what you could find about each of the people in this room. A bit more searching through the profile and there's a photo of their office. They were working on the third floor. And you can also see some photos from his business companion where he has a taste in a certain kind of image. It turns out he's a member of the Russian Adult Webmasters Federation. But this is where our investigation starts to slow down. The cybercriminals have locked down their profiles quite well. And herein is the greatest lesson of social media and mobile devices for all of us right now. Our friends, our families and our colleagues can break our security even when we do the right things. This is MobSoft, one of the companies that this cybercriminal gang owned, and an interesting thing about MobSoft is the 50-percent owner of this posted a job advert, and this job advert matched one of the telephone numbers from the code earlier. This woman was Maria, and Maria is the wife of one of our cybercriminals. And it's kind of like she went into her social media settings and clicked on every option imaginable to make herself really, really insecure. By the end of the investigation, where you can read the full 27-page report at that link, we had photos of the cybercriminals, even the office Christmas party when they were out on an outing. That's right, cybercriminals do have Christmas parties, as it turns out. Now you're probably wondering what happened to these guys. Let me come back to that in just a minute. I want to change pace to one last little demonstration, a technique that is wonderfully simple and basic, but is interesting in exposing how much information we're all giving away, and it's relevant because it applies to us as a TED audience. This is normally when people start kind of shuffling in their pockets trying to turn their phones onto airplane mode desperately. Many of you all know about the concept of scanning for wireless networks. You do it every time you take out your iPhone or your Blackberry and connect to something like TEDAttendees. But what you might not know is that you're also beaming out a list of networks you've previously connected to, even when you're not using wireless actively. So I ran a little scan. I was relatively inhibited compared to the cybercriminals, who wouldn't be so concerned by law, and here you can see my mobile device. Okay? So you can see a list of wireless networks. TEDAttendees, HyattLB. Where do you think I'm staying? My home network, PrettyFlyForAWifi, which I think is a great name. Sophos_Visitors, SANSEMEA, companies I work with. Loganwifi, that's in Boston. HiltonLondon. CIASurveillanceVan. We called it that at one of our conferences because we thought that would freak people out, which is quite fun. This is how geeks party. So let's make this a little bit more interesting. Let's talk about you. Twenty-three percent of you have been to Starbucks recently and used the wireless network. Things get more interesting. Forty-six percent of you I could link to a business, XYZ Employee network. This isn't an exact science, but it gets pretty accurate. Seven hundred and sixty-one of you I could identify a hotel you'd been to recently, absolutely with pinpoint precision somewhere on the globe. Two hundred and thirty-four of you, well, I know where you live. Your wireless network name is so unique that I was able to pinpoint it using data available openly on the Internet with no hacking or clever, clever tricks. And I should mention as well that some of you do use your names, "James Lyne's iPhone," for example. And two percent of you have a tendency to extreme profanity. So something for you to think about: As we adopt these new applications and mobile devices, as we play with these shiny new toys, how much are we trading off convenience for privacy and security? Next time you install something, look at the settings and ask yourself, "Is this information that I want to share? Would someone be able to abuse it?" We also need to think very carefully about how we develop our future talent pool. You see, technology's changing at a staggering rate, and that 250,000 pieces of malware won't stay the same for long. There's a very concerning trend that whilst many people coming out of schools now are much more technology-savvy, they know how to use technology, fewer and fewer people are following the feeder subjects to know how that technology works under the covers. In the U.K., a 60 percent reduction since 2003, and there are similar statistics all over the world. We also need to think about the legal issues in this area. The cybercriminals I talked about, despite theft of millions of dollars, actually still haven't been arrested, and at this point possibly never will. Most laws are national in their implementation, despite cybercrime conventions, where the Internet is borderless and international by definition. Countries do not agree, which makes this area exceptionally challenging from a legal perspective. But my biggest ask is this: You see, you're going to leave here and you're going to see some astonishing stories in the news. You're going to read about malware doing incredible and terrifying, scary things. However, 99 percent of it works because people fail to do the basics. So my ask is this: Go online, find these simple best practices, find out how to update and patch your computer. Get a secure password. Make sure you use a different password on each of your sites and services online. Find these resources. Apply them. The Internet is a fantastic resource for business, for political expression, for art and for learning. Help me and the security community make life much, much more difficult for cybercriminals. Thank you. (Applause)
¿No es increíble cuánto control pueden conseguir los atacantes con tan solo una simple operación? Les mostraré cómo la mayoría de malware cómo se distribuye hoy. Lo que haré es abrir un sitio web que escribí. Es un sitio terrible. Tiene gráficos realmente horribles. Y tiene una sección de comentarios aquí donde nosotros podemos publicar comentarios a la página web. Muchos de Uds. habrán usado antes algo de esto. Desafortunadamente, cuando se implementó, el desarrollador estaba un poco ebrio y consiguió olvidar todas las prácticas de codificación seguras que había aprendido. Entonces imaginemos que nuestro atacante, llamado Pirata Malvado solo por valor cómico, inserta algo un poco desagradable. Este es un script. Es el código que se reproduce en la página web. Así que enviaré este correo, y luego, en la computadora de mi víctima, abriré el navegador web e iré a mi sitio web, www.incrediblyhacked.com. Vean que después de un par de segundos, me redirecciona. La dirección del sitio web en la parte superior que solo puede ver, microshaft.com, el navegador se bloquea mientras golpea uno de estos paquetes explosivos y aparece un antivirus falso. Este es un virus que hace como si fuere software antivirus, analizará y escaneará el sistema, miren lo que está apareciendo aquí. Crea algunas alertas muy serias. Miren, un servidor proxy para porno infantil. Realmente deberíamos limpiar esto. Lo que es muy insultante acerca de esto es que no solo proporcionan a los atacantes acceso a sus datos, sino que, cuando la exploración termina, dicen con el fin de limpiar los virus falsos, Ud. tiene que registrar el producto. Me gustaba más cuando los virus eran gratis. (Risas) La gente ahora paga a los ciberdelincuentes dinero para ejecutar los virus, lo que me parece totalmente extraño. De todos modos, déjenme cambiar de ritmo un poco. Perseguir 250 000 piezas de malware al día es un desafío enorme, y esos números no hacen más que crecer directamente en proporción a la longitud de la línea de mi estrés, como Uds. podrán ver aquí. Así que quiero hablarles brevemente acerca de un grupo de piratas a los que rastreamos durante un año y pillamos... y esto es una suerte inusual en nuestro trabajo. Esto fue una colaboración intersectorial, de gente de Facebook, investigadores independientes, tipos de Sophos. Aquí tenemos un par de documentos que habían subido los ciberdelincuentes para un servicio en la nube, como Dropbox o SkyDrive, como muchos de Uds. quizá usan. En la parte superior, Uds. verán una sección de código fuente. Lo que haría es enviar a los ciberdelincuentes un mensaje de texto cada día diciéndoles cuánto dinero habían hecho ese día, así una especie de informe de facturación ciberdelictivo. Si se fijan bien, notarán una serie que corresponde a números de teléfono rusos. Ahora eso es obviamente interesante, porque nos da una pista de cómo encontrar a los ciberdelincuentes. Abajo, resaltado en rojo, en la otra sección del código fuente, está este "leded:leded". Es el nombre de un usuario, como el que quizá se tenga en Twitter. Así que veremos esto un poco más a fondo. Hay otras piezas interesantes que habían subido los ciberdelincuentes. Muchos de Uds. aquí usarán teléfonos inteligentes para tomar fotos de la conferencia y publicarlas. Una característica interesante de muchos de los teléfonos inteligentes modernos es que al tomar la foto, incrusta datos del GPS sobre dónde se hizo la foto. De hecho, he pasado mucho tiempo visitando sitios de citas en Internet, obviamente para fines de investigación, y me he dado cuenta de que aproximadamente el 60 % de las fotos de perfil en los sitios de citas por Internet contienen las coordenadas GPS de donde se hizo la foto, que da un poco de miedo porque no le darías tu dirección a un montón de extraños, pero estamos muy contentos de dar las coordenadas de GPS con una precisión de más o menos 15 metros. Y nuestros ciberdelincuentes habían hecho lo mismo. Así que aquí hay una foto realizada en San Petersburgo. Luego desplegamos la herramienta de piratería increíblemente avanzada. Utilizamos Google. Utilizando la dirección de correo electrónico, el número de teléfono y los datos del GPS, a la izquierda verán un anuncio para un BMW que vende uno de los ciberdelincuentes. En el otro lado hay un anuncio para vender gatitos sphynx. Uno de estos me parecía demasiado estereotipado. Algo más de búsqueda y aquí está nuestro ciberdelincuente. Imaginen, estos son ciberdelincuentes endurecidos apenas compartiendo información. Imaginen lo que uno podría descubrir sobre cada una de las personas en esta sala. Buscando un poco más a través del perfil se ve una foto de su oficina. Trabajaban en el tercer piso. Y también pueden ver algunas fotos de su compañero de negocios donde él aporta una prueba en un imagen concreta. Se trata de un miembro de la Federación Rusa de Webmasters para Adultos. Pero aquí es donde nuestra investigación comienza a ralentizarse. Los ciberdelincuentes han cerrado sus perfiles bastante bien. Y aquí está la lección más grande de las redes sociales y dispositivos móviles para todos nosotros ahora mismo. Nuestros amigos, nuestras familias y nuestros colegas pueden violar nuestra seguridad aun haciendo las cosas bien. Se trata de MobSoft, una de las empresas perteneciente a esta pandilla del cibercrimen, y una cosa interesante sobre MobSoft es que el dueño del 50 % de la empresa publicó un anuncio de trabajo, y este anuncio de trabajo correspondía a uno de los números de teléfono en el código anterior. Esta mujer es María, y María es la esposa de uno de los ciberdelincuentes. Y es así como entró en su configuración de las redes sociales y hago clic en cualquiera de las opciones imaginables para ponerse realmente, en una situación insegura. Al final de la investigación, donde se puede leer el informe completo de 27 páginas en ese vínculo, tenemos fotos de los ciberdelincuentes, incluso de la fiesta de Navidad en la oficina o cuando estuvieron de excursión. Y es verdad, los ciberdelincuentes celebran fiestas de Navidad, como se ve. Ahora se preguntarán qué pasó con estos muchachos. Déjenme volver a ello en un minuto. Quiero cambiar el ritmo con una última demostración, una técnica que es muy simple y básica, pero es interesante exponer cuánta información regalamos todos, y es relevante porque es aplicable a nosotros como audiencia de TED. Esto sucede cuando la gente empieza a hurgar en los bolsillos tratando de cambiar en modo avión en el teléfono desesperadamente. Muchos de Uds. saben sobre el concepto de buscar redes inalámbricas. Lo hacemos cada vez que sacamos el iPhone o el Blackberry y que nos conectamos a TEDAttendees, por ejemplo. Pero lo que quizá no saben es que también envían información de la lista de redes a las que se hayan conectado previamente incluso aun cuando no usen la red inalámbrica activamente. Así que hice un pequeño análisis. Estaba relativamente limitado en comparación con los ciberdelincuentes, que no se preocupan tanto por la ley, y aquí pueden ver mi dispositivo móvil. ¿De acuerdo? ¿Pueden ver una lista de redes inalámbricas. TEDAttendees, HyattLB. ¿Dónde creen que me hospedo? Mi red doméstica, PrettyFlyForAWifi, creo que es un nombre fantástico. Sophos_Visitors, SANSEMEA, las empresas con la que trabajo. Loganwifi, que se encuentra en Boston. HiltonLondon. CIASurveillanceVan. Lo llamamos así en una de nuestras conferencias porque pensamos que podría asustar a la gente lo que es muy divertido. Esto es como una fiesta de frikis. Pero hagamos esto un poco más interesante. Hablemos de Uds. 23 % de Uds. estuvieron en Starbucks recientemente y utilizaron la red inalámbrica. Las cosas se ponen más interesantes. A 46 % de Uds. yo los podría vincular a su empresa. Red de empleados de XYZ. Esto no es una ciencia exacta, pero consigue bastante precisión. Identifiqué que 761 de Uds. habían estado recientemente en un hotel absolutamente con precisión milimétrica en algún lugar en el mundo. Sé dónde viven 234 de Uds. Su nombre de red inalámbrica es tan único que fui capaz de identificarlo utilizando datos disponibles abiertamente en Internet sin pirateos ni trucos sofisticados e inteligentes. Y debo mencionar también algunos de Uds. usan sus nombres, "IPhone de James Lyne", por ejemplo. Y 2 % de Uds. tienen una tendencia extrema a lo profano. Algo en lo que Uds. deberían pensar: Al incorporar el uso de estas nuevas aplicaciones y dispositivos móviles, y al jugar con estos nuevos juguetes brillantes, ¿cuánto privacidad y seguridad arriesgamos para nuestra conveniencia? La próxima vez que instalen algo, miren la configuración y pregúntense, "¿Es la información que quiero compartir? ¿Alguien podría utilizarla indebidamente?" También tenemos que pensar con precaución cómo podemos desarrollar nuestro futuro talento. Ya ven, la tecnología cambia a una velocidad asombrosa, y las 250 000 piezas de malware no serán las mismas por mucho tiempo. Hay una tendencia muy preocupante, que muchas personas que acaban la escuela saben mucho de tecnología, saben cómo usar la tecnología, pero menos y menos personas están al tanto del proceso para saber cómo funciona la tecnología entre bambalinas. En el Reino Unido, una reducción del 60 % desde el 2003, y hay estadísticas similares en todo el mundo. También tenemos que pensar en los problemas legales en este ámbito. Los ciberdelincuentes de los que hablé, a pesar del robo de millones de dólares, en realidad todavía no han sido arrestados, y a este punto, posiblemente nunca lo serán. La mayoría de las leyes se implementan a nivel nacional, a pesar de los convenios de ciberdelincuencia, donde Internet es internacional por definición y sin fronteras. Los países no están de acuerdo en abordar esta cuestión excepcionalmente difícil desde una perspectiva jurídica. Pero mi pregunta más amplia es: Uds. saldrán de aquí y verán algunas historias asombrosas en las noticias. Leerán sobre el malware que hace cosas increíbles, aterradoras e intimidantes. Sin embargo, el 99 % de esto funciona porque la gente falla en hacer lo básico. Entonces mi pregunta es: ya en línea, encuentren las mejores prácticas sencillas, averigüen cómo actualizar y reparar su computadora. Obtengan una contraseña segura. Asegúrense de utilizar una contraseña diferente en cada uno de sus sitios y servicios en línea. Encuentren estos recursos. Aplíquenlos. Internet es un recurso fantástico para los negocios, para la expresión política, para el arte y para el aprendizaje. Contribuyan a una comunidad segura hagan la vida mucho, mucho más difícil a los ciberdelincuentes. Gracias. (Aplausos)